different manner because I had my
accounting background and so it was more
from a holistic standpoint and not
necessarily from a
sales uh perspective and and I still
believe in that to this day you know I
also have some good mentors as well so
it it goes a long
way and when you
um when you started talking to people
about tax that's obviously because you
were reading the book and you know you
were being mentored by your dad and Etc
so is that why that inclination to
mention it came up you know because the
inclination to mention it came up
because it was relevant right I mean
you're talking about everything has a
tax ramification everything um and and
you know you start a business and had
you gotta pay taxes on your business you
might have to pay some some fees to get
the business going you might have to pay
the state or or the government to even
form an entity uh you know like an LLC
or Corporation or something like that
so it it comes into play in everything
um and most financial advisors some of
them do but most of them don't have a
clue don't think about it and that's
part of the reason like if you ever
watch any investment or even sometimes
life insurance commercials they'll
always say past performance is not an
indicator of future results before you
make any investment or before you make
any investment purchases please consult
your tax or inlegal Consultants or
advisor something along those lines and
it was like wow they're doing these
disclaimers that say go talk to your tax
guy but we're actually talking to them
about things that are going to impact
them from a tax perspective but nobody's
talking about that so in my in my
opinion I almost took it like it was
malpractice to a certain degree um and
then so to me it should be holistic we
want to talk about your taxes we want to
talk about your life insurance we want
to talk about your Investments we want
to talk about your business I mean if
you're really talking to somebody that's
going to advise you and help you they
shouldn't be there to sell you something
they should be there to to advise and
consult and and be a trusted advisor
who's not just there for a commission
now don't get me wrong everybody needs
to get paid right right I'm not trying
to say we're supposed to give it away
but what happens a lot of times is um
people will talk about um they're doing
estate
planning um just to get to the life
insurance
sale and it can be it can be frustrating
now you know the laws have changed and
such you know recently so it's not as
pending do you guys have estate tax in
Canada well we have like when somebody
dies you gotta pay for for whatever is
rainy yes that's what um Ricardo was
saying on yesterday's uh tests show U
that the CRA is pretty they're pretty
gang okay we are live do you have
headphones
yeah I'm hearing
Echo okay sounds good
how many people can you bring on I could
bring
seven nice yeah because yeah with um
with OBS you can't
bring with OBS you can't bring uh uh
people in you have to use like wirecast
or something to link it through yeah I
saw somebody use zoom and um and
OBS yeah but it's just too much you know
like when you're trying to get to the
the show there's just too many there's
too many moving
Parts you know what I mean can you test
your mic one more time check one two
three four five six okay it's working so
let's see how can I switch my headphone
too
so you know how it usually gives you an
option to
uh which because I have an output on my
headphone that I could use yeah an
output um it just microphone it doesn't
give me headphone or or
anything shoot and I can't I can't see
what you see
huh let me just see if I can pull it
up what what browser are you
using Chrome using Chrome yeah uh you
don't see the um can you see the the
little
gear yeah or the uh the not necessarily
the gear but can you see
the cam camera on the very top of the
URL yeah if you click that you should be
able
to well that just mutes yeah that just
turns my camera off that turns my mic
off it's the uh I wonder if I change it
in my
main and you saw the gear and you saw
the the microphone so if you click the
microphone I fig yeah you got it okay
hold on one second
can you hear me yeah I can hear you
that's a nice mic that you
got yeah this is uh audio Technic 2020 I
need to get a new swing
arm the sucker is uh seeing better days
oh yeah you should see should see mine
over here I have a you know cuz like I
record music and stuff and like this
thing just gets in my way and it keeps
on falling and I have to I have to to
get it repaired so I can use the mic
again but okay there I am yeah this is
pretty cool yeah and there's no leg cuz
yesterday there was a
lag n there's a little lag you see a leg
Yeah I'm watching it from my
phone I don't think you can help the
latency though I think that's just
that's just kind of part of it yeah yeah
I mean it is what it is I mean the
beautiful thing is you're in Canada and
I'm in excuse me I'm in Philadelphia
right so yeah that's crazy well I mean
and we've known each other that's like a
lot of these these friendships all stem
from you know blab it's crazy uh do you
remember uh uh Lon
Murray no she was the IP
attorney well anyway she's the IP
attorney she's out of Alabama and I had
her on the money hour the other day and
we talked all about IP you know
trademarks patents uh copyrights but
that started a couple years ago on blab
it's funny I don't even remember how
many years ago that was now at this
point that's I think is like around the
time I met you was uh probably two and a
half years ago yeah two and a half three
years ago yeah you're probably right
yeah yeah that's funny that's funny time
is ticking I mean like I was really
distraught with the whole blab um going
down because like you know the the sense
of community that you got um with
everybody and just meeting people that
you never would ever meet in your life
you know and being able to have those
like those honest exchanges with people
you know I kind of miss that but at the
same time like I wouldn't be here hadn't
it not been for you know them sparking
that you know that movement and I know a
lot like just like you and a lot of
other people they are all kind of
getting together and and you know doing
their live stream thing and they seem to
be ahead of a lot of people that are
adopting now that you know Facebook has
allowed people to you know yeah how
about that yeah I I agree I don't know
if you remember the guy I used to do the
show with my Monday Mondays uh Eddie
Eddie Coulson yeah now now he's got a
whole um uh wholesale
uh real estate wholesale on YouTube so I
remember Eddie was like man how do you
have time to do all this content stuff
said I love it it's it's great it's
awesome cuz I started on I started on
radio so I just kind of developed the
natural love for social media and for
all the uh the audio uh stuff because I
was interviewing people live on radio I
just kind of fell in love with it right
right right tell people now I don't know
if we got an audience we got three
people watching right now so hi everyone
we're just testing we're just testing
out two people on the camera I just want
to see if there's any latency in my
voice like if I'm talking does The Voice
match my lips um and if I bring more
people on does it degrade the um uh does
it degrade the broadcast just let me
know in the comments below uh but yeah
this is uh Kamari Ellis uh welcome to uh
hustles on TV my friend thank you for
having me sir you've been doing hustle
zone for a long time you've been
hustling the zone for a long
time yeah man and um and I've you've
been doing your own show and uh you know
I know that you're in the the the the
financial world and uh you know you're
pretty big a big figure because when I
when I watch what you're doing you you
you're doing symposiums you're on panels
um you know you're doing some big things
over there where are you from I'm from
Philadelphia Pennsylvania and the US OFA
I don't know if I would be a consider
myself a big figure but thank you you
know all the same I'm just trying to do
my part yeah well you seem pretty active
now uh let's dial it back a little bit
where like how did you get into the
financial game what what because it
seems like uh you know every time I I
watch your stuff I'm like man I want to
know his story like where did did where
did it where did it spark in him that he
wanted to help other people with their
Finance uh I was born into it so my
father is an accountant um I believe
y'all call him accountants in um in
Canada my my father was an accountant
worked with a lot of small business
owners a lot of individuals
and you know he had his own business and
I would have to go to his office a lot
of times every day after school because
my mom would be at work and so when I
would be at his office I would be down
there wrecking Havoc you know eight
years old nine years old I'm shooting
rubber bands all over the place I'm
entertaining myself paper clips you know
was funny I'm I'm 40ish now and so he
said I found some I found some paper
clips the other day from when you
shaoting around so you know we we I did
a lot of mischievous things to entertain
myself and he said one day read this
book you're going to learn how to do
taxes and so I I read the book hey buddy
how you doing I read the book and uh and
um I started do taxes now I kind of
rebelled against it I didn't want to do
it but you know all the all the while it
it it really helped me um because I've
been around business I've been around
different different people for the
longest time so it it was definitely a
help so when did when did it start
clicking in for you cuz obviously our
parents teach us things that we want to
rebel against and we we get a little bit
annoyed when they're trying to push it
down you know our throats but when did
you start when did it start when did you
get that that breaking point or that
breaking moment you're like aha like you
know this is power uh that's
uh that's a great question so I had to
run my dad's office when I was like
20 two-ish for a couple years um and I
was in tech at the same time and so I I
ran this business I was in tech at the
same time I got laid off from Tech and I
decided to go back to school because I
hadn't going to college and so I'm not
sure how old you are righty but this was
during the time back in the late 90s
early 2000s where you know if you knew
any networking at all or how to put
together computer you could get a job in
um in Tech and I became a network
engineer so it's still I just wanted to
make money but then when I ran my dad's
office I kind of saw some of the impact
I would have on people um the positive
impact I would have on people positive
impact I would have on people's lives I
mean there was one guy um and I was
really young a friend of mine's dad was
being garnished by the IRS and that's
the taxing agency down here in the
United
States they he so 70 grand and they had
been taking his money for like two years
and by the time I had gone back and done
all his taxes they gave him a refund and
it was just like wow this is this is
pretty cool but I still wasn't sold at
that point um and what happened was I
went to school fish School majored in
finance um went to work as a financial
advisor so I got like all my life
insurance licenses all my Securities
licenses which by the way are only
they're they're sales tools they're not
necessarily they don't necessarily make
you good uh a good investor they just
say hey you can sell these products and
servic to people but I did that and then
I got an opportunity to become an
investment
analyst um and while I was a financial
advisor and then I transitioned over and
then I became a portfolio manager on the
institutional side so I was managing
money uh at both some of the
institutions uh they both had about2
billion dollar under management
did that for a while I'm just realized
well I kind of have a great swath of
experience and
education uh wind up going out on my own
with a partners with some
partners that didn't work and then here
I am now so I guess the spark
started somewhere when I became a
financial advisor because when I became
a financial advisor the guys for the
most part were focus on selling products
you know selling the life insurance
selling the mutual funds but they would
never talk about tax and I'm like how do
you not talk about tax where tax is a
major uh impact on anybody's financial
situation and so a lot of times with
that and I'm a nerd too um so I always
read a lot uh with that I was able to
talk to clients kind of in a different
manner because I had my accounting
background and so it was more from a
holistic standpoint and not necessarily
from a sales
uh perspective and and I still believe
in that to this day you know I also have
some good mentors as well so it it goes
a long
way and when you
um when you started talking to people
about tax that's obviously because you
were reading the book and you know you
being mentored by your dad and Etc so is
that why that inclination to mention it
came up you know because the inclination
to mention it came up because it was
relevant right I mean you're talking
about every Everything has a tax
ramification everything um and and you
know you start a business and you gotta
pay taxes on your business you you might
have to pay some some fees to get the
business going you might have to pay the
state or or the government to even form
an entity uh you know like an LLC or
Corporation or something like that so
but it it comes into play and everything
um and most financial advisors some of
them do but most of them don't have a
clue
don't think about it and that's part of
the reason like if you ever watch any
investment or even sometimes life
insurance commercials they'll always say
past performance is not an indicator of
future results before you make any
investment or before you make any
investment purchases please consult your
tax or inlegal Consultants or advisors
something along those lines and it was
like wow they're doing these disclaimers
that say go talk to your tax guy but
we're actually talking to them about
things that are going to impact them
from a tax perspective but nobody's
talking about that so in my in my
opinion I almost took it like it was
malpractice to a certain degree um and
then so to me it should be holistic we
want to talk about your taxes we want to
talk about your life insurance we want
to talk about your Investments we want
to talk about your business I mean if
you're really talking to somebody that's
going to advise you and help you they
shouldn't be there to sell you something
they should be there to to advise and
consult and and be trusted advisor who's
not just there for a commission now
don't get me wrong everybody needs to
get paid right right I'm not trying to
say we're supposed to give it away but
what happens a lot of times is um people
will talk about um they're doing estate
planning um just to get to the life
insurance
sale and it can be it can be frustrating
now you know the laws of changed as such
you know recently so it's not as pending
do you guys have EST state tax in Canada
well we have a somebody dies you got to
pay for for whatever is raining yes
that's what um Ricardo was saying on
yesterday's uh test show U that the CRA
is pretty they're pretty gangster when
it comes to that kind of stuff so when
you when you when you die you know you
got a pony up right what's the CRA what
do that stand for Canadian uh Canada
Revenue Agency oh okay so is that like
our IRS down here yeah okay all right
all right yeah yeah
yeah everybody wants to get paid but at
least you guys get free
healthare you know what I I I can't
complain with that I mean I I there's
some there's some aspects of My Health
Care system that I don't like but you
know I I was born with asthma and his
eczema and allergic to everything under
the sun and you know hadn't it not been
my mom could not afford no uh you know
health insurance or whatever so I'm
really lucky that you know that we have
the free healthare that's for sure yes I
get I get accused of being a Republican
and then I get accused of being a
liberal um but I I I do I do because I
think I'm a Centrist right I'm in the
middle I I do I do think it's
interesting know that at least in the
United States that a lot of people go
bankrupt because of Health Care cost and
you're not wanting to address
that or being called a socialist or
Marxist because you want to address that
or give some relief to the people I find
that really interesting so I think
Canada's got it right of course
nothing's going to be perfect there
always going to be something that can be
better right that's just life yeah but
you know I I think y'all got the healthc
care part right I know y'all pay a
little bit more taxes but what if many
Americans don't realize this we're over
taxed ourselves we pay tax on uh real
estate tax you know for your home cell
phones there's a hidden tax there um
gasoline is a tax there you know you
name it there's probably a tax on it so
it's not just your simple you know when
you get your paycheck they take out your
federal wage tax we get taxed on
everything you get tax on everything and
that that being said Warren Buffett has
been known to say that you know he he
pays less tax than his secretary what do
what do you think about
that oh I mean he does his his overall
tax rate is lower than his secretaries
um you know the rich get to take
advantage of a lot of loopholes that the
poor don't or the the middle class don't
um I get it uh most of his money is tied
up in birkshire haway which is a a big-
Time Corporation so Warden gets a a
meager salary in comparison to his
overall net worth I think he takes home
somewhere between 400 and 500,000 a year
now he makes a lot of money off of
dividends because of his uh birkshire
haway ownership but he only gets paid
that when you look at the rest of the uh
Wall Street crew they're getting two
three four 5 20 million dollar a year um
so you know it's it's a little different
but I I'm a big fan of Warren um some of
some of his investment philosophies I've
adopted as my own um who were really
came from Graham that he kind of re
reformulated right but I I like I like
Buffett a lot I think he's on the right
side of History his wife actually um his
first wife actually helped uh to to get
him to be more I guess socially uh
conscious right so because him and him
and um Bill Gates are doing you know the
the big giving program I can't think of
the name of it right now but you know
they're giving back most of their most
of their net worth most of their wealth
when they pass away and they're not
leaving it all to their family they're
not trying to create these super big
dynasties like the Rothchilds the
kennedies and the Vanderbilts they they
want to try to do better for
society so they say anyway I believe
them yeah I I believe them too and uh
what do you think about Warren Buffett
saying that you know the rich should be
taxed
more um I I I think in this country I
can't speak for Canada right but in this
country the founding fathers or the
rebels that they were at the time were
business owners right they were land
owners they were farmers so what what
wind up happening is everything in the
system kind of kind of Lent itself to
business ownership uh and land ownership
and so if you are if you are not in line
with
that you're GNA you're going to suffer
financially um but yeah the so the rich
many times do get to take advantage of
these these tax loopholes they are the
land owners they are the business owners
and they are able to take advantage of
that but you know your average
individuals can take advantage of some
of these things too now I'm not the guy
who tries to sell stuff and say hey the
wealthy you're doing this you should you
should do it too I think that's a
fallacy in many in many ways but I do
think there are some things that you can
do individual that you know might have
uh meager earnings but you can still
align yourself with um getting taxed
more favorably or or at least being able
to take advantage of more to take
advantage of more tax loopholes or or
tax um tax situations that favor
business owners and
investors you just you just have to
think about it in that in that light but
many don't many don't that's why I'm
kind on a crusade to uh to educate
people more so than to sell them
products M and going back to um before I
asked my other question uh you said that
you you a lot of your practice said you
favor or a lot of your investment
practice uh uh favors Warren Buffett's
philosophy about um fundamental
investing um are you tell me a little
bit about what you think about
fundamental investing as opposed to
speculative
investing well you can still be a
fundamentalist and still speculate um so
I I am in so when it comes to beginning
investors I think everybody should
follow waren Buffett which is basically
a Buy and Hold buy things you know buy
things you understand and buy them for
the Long Haul um you see a lot of
advertisements for people doing trading
uh crypto and things like that that's
all fine but to me those are all more
ADV intermediate SL to Advan uh place to
go um when you look at Warren and what
Warren's done by just buying and holding
I mean he's created a fortune now you
know for disclosure that that fortune
was made off the backs of other people's
money as well right but you can you can
do well just buying and holding um and
you can get lucky recently I recommended
a company that's going to take advantage
of Canada's uh uh recreational marijuana
that's going online in in October called
tillay done over 200% and last in the
last 45 days right but I'm not looking
to sell um I'm looking it's a long-term
hold it's it's I'm looking forward to be
10 years long so I mean I think people
should should start with things they
know begin to understand the business um
and then you could do some of the fancy
stuff I think sometimes we try to get
too fancy too quick too
soon so going back to a little bit of
your ear I don't know if I your question
about Warren buff though in fundamental
versus speculation now I I don't know if
you did I was just falling
love I was I was just uh just being
honest yeah no no but I understand uh
and a lot of the things that you're
saying makes make sense uh and I don't
think I mean Warren Warren is you know
he he he has said it in um previous
interviews that you know he was lucky
you know he was lucky to be a white man
he was lucky to grow up in the time that
he did he's lucky for his intelligence
and you know for his passion so you know
as much as we all want to be like Warren
Buffett I don't think that you know we
can but at the same time we can learn
from him and I mean the information's
there and the one thing I like about
Warren Buffett is that he says he reads
everything you know he does yeah yeah he
does supposed he spends like eight hours
a day reading I don't know how he does
it it would drive me crazy and I like to
read so I'm just I'm not worthy I'm not
worthy I got dyslexia I can't do that so
I'm like listening to uh you know audio
books and having things read to me but
still I don't have the patience to to
sit there but that's probably the reason
why he's rich and why I'm still uh you
know I think part of is generational too
um they were more so conditioned to read
uh more so I think than we were and I
and I will read I do read a lot um but I
I I I think a lot of his generational as
well yeah you know what I'm going to
have to put an end to this broadcast I
think that this went well uh for the
test I would love to actually bring you
on on a weekly basis on the YouTube
channel and chat because I think that
you have a lot of insightful things to
say and I think a lot of people could
learn um would you be open to to being a
guest it just depends on the day but
yeah I'd love to be a
guest yeah I will uh I'll hit you up
I'll let you know that the dates once
I'm able to go live again on YouTube
they banned me from going live because I
uploaded a video without any context and
they're like this is against our
policies um because I was yeah there was
a video of a woman that was uh cuz I've
done it before on my channel and I
talked about you know abuse where a
woman was hitting her child in in broad
daylight but I didn't add enough context
to the video so it just looked like it
was hate speech or not hate speech but
it looked like it was just me promoting
violence so they they D me for 90 days
oh wow okay gotcha yeah you gotta be
careful with that I've gotten a couple
strikes over there but uh thanks for
having me on man I appreciate it yeah
thanks a lot and yeah I I really want to
have you on again and get into more
in-depth conversations because I think
uh you know especially people in my
community we need to learn more about it
because we don't really talk about
finances and a lot of it is hush hush
and
and uh until it's too late so whatever
way I can help I I'll definitely do that
with this channel so uh thank you so
much Kamari for coming on and uh I'll
talk to you later all right buddy have a
good one yeah see
you okay so are you guys still
here that was pretty that was pretty
awesome I got to go tuck my son into bed
uh this was a great discussion I'm going
take some clips and throw it on my
social media um this was awesome this it
worked great Anna tell me if the lag
still exists um like was there a lag in
my voice was there a a huge lag um um
let me know I'm going to just test it
out right
now oh
still this this actually was good
wirecast is
good and
this was
great I'm just I'm just testing testing
testing
testing okay all right have a good one
talk to you later bye